♪〜
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original
Interviews with Monster Girls
The class is astir
I want to let myself go too,
But I end up putting on a fake smile.
Your eyes alone conveyed a competitive spirit
Biting at your lip forcefully.
You once said,
"I wouldn't want to worry what someone thinks
And end up hurting someone else in the process!"
When the chime rings out, as the rain lifts up,
We'll pass the boundaries of our school!
Jumping through the puddles, light will scatter about
Our smiles, and wishes will be so bright!
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original!
〜♪
（高橋(たかはし)）ハア ハア ハア…
あっ
起きる[おきる]:to get up|to wake up|to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents)
（高橋）あっ！
（ひかり）あっ 起きた
Oh, you're awake.
Good morning...
（ひかり）おっはよ〜
Sorry. Did I wake you up?
起こす[おこす]:to raise|to wake|to cause||
（ひかり）
ごめん 起こしちゃった？
Demis Want to Swim
No, it's fine... Did you need something?
用[よう]:business|use|for the use of ...|
（高橋）
ああ いや 大丈夫だ　何か用か？
質問[しつもん]:question/inquiry/enquiry
（ひかり）うん　質問 質問！
Yeah! I have a question!
Wow, your eyes really do shine.
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 光る[ひかる]:to shine/to glitter/to be bright
（高橋）
お〜 ホントに目が光っている
Would this be why vampires can see so well at night?
写真[しゃしん]:photograph/photo|movie, バンパイア:vampire, 夜[よる, よ]:evening/night, 夜[や]:counter for nights, 理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
この写真が バンパイアが
夜でも目がいいって理由になるの？
Yeah, it's the same as for nocturnal animals.
夜行性[やこうせい]:nocturnality/nocturnal habits, 動物[どうぶつ]:animal, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 理屈[りくつ]:theory/reason
ああ 夜行性の動物なんかと
同じ理屈だ
動物[どうぶつ]:animal, 眼球[がんきゅう]:eyeball, 奥[おく]:inner part/inside/interior
そういう動物には
眼球の奥に
Nocturnal animals have a mirror-like layer at the back of their eyes.
鏡[かがみ]:mirror/looking-glass|barrel head, 層[そう]:layer|sheaf|storey (of a building)
鏡のような層が
あってだな
That layer reflects the light that enters through the retina,
層[そう]:layer|sheaf|storey (of a building), 網膜[もうまく]:retina, 光[ひかり]:light|illumination|happiness||
その層が
網膜から入ってきた光を
反射[はんしゃ]:reflection/reverberation|reflex, わずか:only/merely/(a) little, 光[ひかり]:light|illumination|happiness||
反射することで
わずかな光でも
allowing them to see clearly, even in the faintest light.
鮮明[せんめい]:vivid/clear/distinct, 見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
鮮明に見えるように
しているんだ
Oh! So that glow you always see in pictures of them...
写真[しゃしん]:photograph/photo|movie, 光る[ひかる]:to shine/to glitter/to be bright
（ひかり）
あっ じゃあ 写真とかでよく見る
光ってるのは…
Their eyes are reflecting the light that humans shine on them.
当てる[あてる]:to hit|to expose|to apply (e.g. patch)||, ライト:light, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 反射[はんしゃ]:reflection/reverberation|reflex
（高橋）
人間が当てるライトなんかが
反射しているだけだ
Wow, that's so cool!
おもしろい:interesting/fascinating|amusing
へえ〜 おもしろ〜！
Vampires probably see well at night for the same reason.
バンパイア:vampire, 夜[よる, よ]:evening/night, 夜[や]:counter for nights, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 構造[こうぞう]:structure/construction/makeup
バンパイアが夜でも目がいいのは
同じ構造だからだろう
I'm so glad I asked you!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（ひかり）先生に聞いて よかった
But that same quality also makes them sensitive to bright light.
敏感[びんかん]:sensitive/alert/aware, 光[ひかり]:light|illumination|happiness||, 弱い[よわい]:weak/frail/delicate
ただ そういった目は
敏感な分 強い光に弱い
I know! That's why you can't take flash photos at the zoo!
動物園[どうぶつえん]:zoo/zoological gardens, フラッシュ:flash, 禁止[きんし]:prohibition/inhibition/ban
（ひかり）
分かってま〜す
動物園では フラッシュ禁止！
Well, that's also true, but...
いや それもそうだが
You should be careful not to damage your eyes.
痛める[いためる]:to hurt|to harm|to worry|, 痛める[やめる]:sick/ill|to hurt, 注意[ちゅうい]:caution/being careful/attention (heed)
お前も 目を痛めないように
注意しろよ
The reason vampires don't handle sunlight well is probably similar.
バンパイア:vampire, 日光[にっこう]:sunlight, 弱い[よわい]:weak/frail/delicate, 似る[にる]:to resemble/to look like|to be similar (in status, condition, etc.), 理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
それとバンパイアが日光に弱いのも
似た理由だろうから
うん
Oh.
On sunny days like today, especially,
特に[とくに]:particularly/especially, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 日ざし[ひざし]:sunlight/rays of the sun
特に 今日みたいな
日ざしの強い日は
you should look out for dizzy spells,
貧血[ひんけつ]:anemia/anaemia, 日焼け[ひやけ]:sunburn/suntan|becoming discolored from the sun (e.g. paper), 対策[たいさく]:measure/provision/step, しっかり:tightly (holding on)/firmly|strongly (built)
貧血だけじゃなく
日焼け対策も しっかりしなきゃな
and also protect yourself from sunburn.
（ひかり）うん
Right.
Also—
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（高橋）あと…
（ひかり）先生
Mr. T?
I already know all that.
そういうのは よく知ってるから
How many years do you think I've been a vampire?
バンパイア:vampire
私 何年バンパイアやってると
思ってるの？
Oh, right... Sorry.
（高橋）ああ そうだな　すまん
It's just, well...
いや その…
Earlier, I had a dream that a vampire attacked me.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, バンパイア:vampire, 襲う[おそう]:to attack|to succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)|to make a sudden visit, 夢を見る[ゆめをみる]:to dream/to have a dream
さっき バンパイアに
襲われる夢を見てな
Was it scary?
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
（ひかり）怖かった？
It made a lot of sense.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), しっくり:exactly/nicely|to be fitting
（高橋）すごく しっくりきた
（ひかり）え？
How do I put it?
なんという:how (beautiful, etc.)
なんというか
It made me think that vampires' tendency to attack in darkness
闇[やみ]:darkness|bewilderment|black-marketeering, 紛れる[まぎれる]:to disappear into|to do something under the cover of (confusion, etc.)|to be almost indistinguishable||, 襲う[おそう]:to attack|to succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)|to make a sudden visit, バンパイア:vampire, 習性[しゅうせい]:habit|behavior/behaviour
闇に紛れて人を襲うという
バンパイアの習性は
is something that comes very naturally.
とても:very/awfully|(not) at all, 自然[しぜん]:nature|natural|naturally
とても自然なものだと思ったんだ
Achieving your goal
短所[たんしょ]:defect/demerit/weak point, カバー:cover/covering/dust jacket, ながら:while/during|while
短所をカバーしながらも
by concealing your weaknesses, while fully using your strengths...
長所[ちょうしょ]:strong point/merit/virtue, 最大限[さいだいげん]:maximum|to the maximum degree, 生かす[いかす]:to make (the best) use of|to let live|to revive, 目的[もくてき]:purpose/goal/aim, 達成[たっせい]:achievement
長所を最大限に生かし
目的を達成する
Just as with animals,
野生[やせい]:wild/growing wild|I, 動物[どうぶつ]:animal
野生動物のような それは
that must be the most comfortable way for vampires to live.
バンパイア:vampire, いちばん:number one/first|best, 伸び伸び[のびのび]:feeling at ease/carefree
バンパイアが
いちばん伸び伸びできる—
生活[せいかつ]:living/life (one's daily existence)/livelihood, スタイル:figure/body build
生活スタイルなんだろう
When I think about it like that, I feel modern vampires,
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
そう考えると
普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train, 合わせる[あわせる]:to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)|to join together|to face||, 現代[げんだい]:nowadays/modern era/modern times, バンパイア:vampire
普通の人間に合わせている
現代のバンパイアは
who adjust themselves to live like humans, must feel constricted.
少[しょう]:small/little/few, 窮屈[きゅうくつ]:narrow|formal|constrained|, 思い[おもい]:thought|imagination|desire||
少なからず 窮屈な思いを
しているんだろうなって
So I ended up giving you a lecture you didn't need.
おせっかい:meddling/meddlesomeness|meddler, 焼く[やく]:to burn|to roast|to heat||, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
つい いらぬおせっかいを
焼いてしまった
Nah, I'm really glad you're concerned for me.
ううん:no|er, well, ..., 気にかける[きにかける]:to weigh on one's mind/to trouble one's heart/to be concerned about, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant
（ひかり）
ううん 気にかけてくれるのは
すごくうれしいよ
However! You're wrong about one thing!
た　だ　し！
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 勘違い[かんちがい]:misunderstanding/wrong guess
先生は１つ勘違いしてる
Stand up!
スタンダップ！
Take off the lab coat!
白衣[はくい, びゃくい]:white robe/(doctor's) white gown, 脱ぐ[ぬぐ]:to take off (clothes, shoes, etc.)/to undress
白衣を脱ぐ！
Wriggle, wriggle, wriggle...
ゴソゴソ:rustling sound/rummaging sound
ゴソゴソ ゴソゴソ
はっ！　へいっ！　てい！
Ta-dah!
じゃじゃ〜ん！
Modern vampires can hunt comfortably, too!
現代[げんだい]:nowadays/modern era/modern times, バンパイア:vampire, 伸び伸び[のびのび]:feeling at ease/carefree, 狩り[かり]:hunting|harvesting (e.g. berries, fruit)/picking
現代のバンパイアだって
伸び伸び 狩りはできるも〜ん
The vampire's white cape flows
白[しろ]:white|innocence|blank space||, 白[しら]:white|unseasoned|very much||, マント:mantle/cloak/manteau, たなびく:to linger/to hover above/to trail
♪ 白マントを たなびかせ
as she searches for her prey!
獲物[えもの]:game/spoils/trophy, 探す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
♪ 獲物を探すぞ
バンパイア:vampire
♪ バンパイア〜 アイ！
むむっ！　あれは？
Is that...
Shiba Shortbread
Yes! Time to attack!
しめた:I've got it/all right/fine, 襲う[おそう]:to attack|to succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)|to make a sudden visit
しめた　襲うぞ！
パンツ:underpants/pants/briefs, 見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
（ひかり）シャ〜！
（高橋）パンツ 見えてるぞ
Your panties are showing.
（ひかり）ウウッ ウウッ
（高橋）すまん！　本当にすまん！
Sorry! I'm really sorry!
著しい[いちじるしい]:striking/remarkable/considerable (used for good, bad, and neutral observations), デリカシー:delicacy/tact/considerateness, 欠ける[かける]:to be chipped|to be lacking|to be insufficient|, 発言[はつげん]:statement/remark/observation
今のは 著しく
デリカシーに欠ける発言だった
That was an extremely insensitive thing to say...
Then, you...
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（ひかり）じゃあ 先生も
You should also do something silly!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, はっちゃける:to make merry and forget one's troubles/to do as one pleases
先生も なんか
はっちゃけたことして
Are you nuts?
（高橋）お前ってヤツは…
Act like a vampire, too!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, バンパイア:vampire
（ひかり）
先生もバンパイアやって！
A vampire?
バンパイア:vampire
バンパイア？
Hiss... I'm going to suck your blood.
血[ち]:blood/consanguinity, 吸う[すう]:to smoke|to suck|to absorb|
シャアア… 血を吸っちゃうぞ
His eyes aren't shining.
光る[ひかる]:to shine/to glitter/to be bright
目が光ってないぞ！
He's a fake vampire! Get him!
偽[にせ]:imitation/fake|pseudo-, 偽[ぎ]:(logic) false, バンパイア:vampire, 襲う[おそう]:to attack|to succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)|to make a sudden visit
偽バンパイアだ　襲え〜！
お前は〜！
You little...
アハハハハ！　アハハッ ハハッ
ハア〜
Oh, I have another favor to ask you...
個[こ, コ]:counter for articles|counter for military units|individual, 個[か, カ]:counter for the ichi-ni-san counting system (usu. directly preceding the item being counted)/a noun read using its on-yomi, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
あっ あと もう１個
先生に お願いがあるんだけど
This Saturday, could we borrow the school pool?
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 土曜[どよう]:Saturday, 学校[がっこう]:school, プール:(swimming) pool, 借りる[かりる]:to borrow/to have a loan|to rent
今度の土曜 学校のプール
借りられないかな？
The school pool is outdoors.
学校[がっこう]:school, プール:(swimming) pool, 屋外[おくがい]:outdoors/alfresco, 屋外[やど]:outside near the door to one's home
学校のプールって 屋外だぞ？
Wouldn't an indoor one be better?
屋内[おくない]:indoor (court, pool, etc.), プール:(swimming) pool
どっかの屋内プールのほうが…
Nah, it's fine!
平気[へいき]:coolness/calmness|all right
平気 平気
まあ できんこともないかな
Well, I guess it wouldn't be impossible.
Really?
ホント:truth/reality/actuality
ホント？
A teacher needs to be present, though.
教師[きょうし]:teacher (classroom), 立ち会い[たちあい]:presence (e.g. of an observer)/observation|trading session (at an exchange), 条件[じょうけん]:condition/conditions/term
教師立ち会いって条件がつくが
That's totally fine.
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, オーケー:OK
全然オーケー
Okay, I'll ask the principal.
校長[こうちょう]:principal/headmaster, 掛け合う[かけあう]:to negotiate with/to talk over with/to haggle
じゃ 校長に掛け合ってみるよ
Yay!
やった〜！
決まる[きまる]:to be decided/to be settled|to look good in (clothes)
まだ決まったわけじゃないからな
That doesn't mean anything is decided yet.
I know! Splish, splish, splash.
（ひかり）は〜い
ジャブジャブ:splashing water sound/with a splash
フフッ　ジャブジャブ すい〜
（高橋）う〜ん
Mr. Takahashi!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（ひまり）高橋先生！
Himari, good timing.
ちょうど:exactly/precisely|as if, ちょうど:supplies/furniture/fixtures
（高橋）
ひまりちゃん ちょうどよかった
聞きたいことが…
I wanted to ask—
I understand you saw my sister's underwear?
下着[したぎ]:underwear
（ひまり）
姉の下着を
見たそうですが
Mr. T saw my panties! Now I can never get married~
Care to explain what this is all about?
どういう:somehow/how/in what way, 説明[せつめい]:explanation/exposition, もらえる:to be able to receive/to be able to take|could you (give me)
どういうことか
説明してもらえますか？
Mr. T saw my panties! Now I can never get married~
I understand now... I'm sorry this keeps happening.
事情[じじょう]:circumstances/consideration/conditions, 何度[なんど]:how many times?/how often?
事情は分かりました
何度もすみません
No, I was partially at fault this time.
今回[こんかい]:now/this time/lately, 落ち度[おちど]:mistake/error/fault
（高橋）
いや 今回は
俺にも落ち度があったから
Sorry for that.
なんか すまん
Anyway, what did you want to ask me?
それで 私に聞きたいこと
というのは？
Oh, that's right.
おう そうだった
It's just, Hikari said she wants to swim in the pool.
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, プール:(swimming) pool, 泳ぐ[およぐ]:to swim
実は ひかりが
プールで泳ぎたいって言っててな
She did?
姉が？
Sunlight is hard on vampires, as it is.
日ざし[ひざし]:sunlight/rays of the sun, 弱い[よわい]:weak/frail/delicate, バンパイア:vampire
（高橋）
ただでさえ 日ざしに弱い
バンパイアが
Wouldn't swimming outdoors be really uncomfortable for her?
屋外[おくがい]:outdoors/alfresco, 屋外[やど]:outside near the door to one's home, 水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers, 相当[そうとう]:befitting|considerable|to be worthy of||, つらい:painful/bitter|tough
屋外で水着は
相当つらいんじゃないのか？
Mr. T saw my panties! Now I can never get married!
It seemed wrong to proceed without permission from you and your parents.
両親[りょうしん, ふたおや]:parents/both parents, 許可[きょか]:permission/approval|to permit, 取る[とる]:to take|to steal|to eat||
ひまりちゃんや ご両親に
許可を取らないで
Mr. T saw my panties! Now I can never get married!
I just heard the whole story from Mr. Takahashi.
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 進める[すすめる]:to advance/to promote/to hasten
話を進めるわけには
いかないと思って
I just heard the whole story from Mr. Takahashi.
I don't see any problem.
いいんじゃないですか？
Yeah, I figured...
やっぱり:too/also|still
ハア〜 やっぱり そうだよな
えっ いいの？
Wait, you don't?
If that's what she wants, it'll be fine.
本人[ほんにん]:the person himself
本人が そうしたいんなら
大丈夫ですよ
The way my sister is...
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression
姉は あんな感じなので
Spending a summer day, just playing around isn't unusual for her.
真夏[まなつ]:midsummer, 遊び歩く[あそびあるく]:to visit one place after another without plan or effect/to gallivant about, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 珍しい[めずらしい]:unusual|new|fine (e.g. gift)
真夏に１日中 遊び歩くなんて
珍しいことじゃありません
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
好きなようにさせてください
Let her do as she pleases.
Really?
そうか
（早紀絵(さきえ)）ハア…
Why don't we go for drinks sometime?
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 飲む[のむ]:to drink|to smoke (tobacco)|to engulf||
今度 飲みにでも行きませんか？
What if we really do end up going?
ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of)
本当に行くことになったら
どうしよう
What should I drink?
飲む[のむ]:to drink|to smoke (tobacco)|to engulf||
何を飲んだら…
I like beer, but that might make me seem like an old man.
ビール:beer, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), っぽい:-ish/-like|tossing something out
ビール好きだけど
おじさんっぽいかも
Cocktails? Shochu highball?
カクテル:cocktail, チューハイ:shochu highball/cocktail of shochu with tonic water
カクテル？　チューハイ？
A lemon highball seems like an old man's drink, too!
っぽい:-ish/-like|tossing something out, 気がする[きがする]:to have a certain mood or feeling/to have a hunch
レモンハイは
おじさんっぽい気がするし…
More importantly, what if something happens due to the alcohol?
いや それよりも！
酔う[よう]:to get drunk|to feel sick (e.g. in a vehicle)|to be elated, 勢い[いきおい]:force|influence|impetus|
酔った勢いで
もしも 何かあったら…
Ugaki
Satou Sakie
What do you think, Ugaki?
どう思いますか？　宇垣(うがき)さん！
Can we talk about this tomorrow?
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
（宇垣）その話 明日でいい？
Ugaki
Goodnight.
おやすみ:holiday/day off|sleep
おやすみ〜
Ah... Wait!
（早紀絵）あっ ちょっと！
Ugaki!
宇垣さん？
ハア〜
Stressing out like this won't do any good...
悩む[なやむ]:to be worried/to be troubled, 一向[ひたすら, ひたぶる]:nothing but/earnest/intent, 一向[いっこう]:completely|(not) at all|earnestly|, 明く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
こうして悩んでいても
一向に らちが明かないよね
Okay!
（早紀絵）よし！
（アラーム音）
I'll just stay positive!
とりあえず:first of all/at once|for now, 前向き[まえむき]:facing forward/front-facing/forward-looking
とりあえず 前向きにいこう！
Go for it! Right now!
攻める[せめる]:to attack/to assault/to assail
攻めよう 今！
Try to appeal to him, even if it takes a little aphrodisiac effect!
多少[たしょう]:more or less/somewhat|amount, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, アピール:appeal (e.g. to public opinion)/plea/request
多少 催淫してでも
高橋先生にアピールする
Mr. Takahashi!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
高橋先生！
Oh, good morning.
おはようございます:good morning
あっ おはようございます
Good morning!
おはようございます:good morning
おはようございます
Th-The other day, in that video,
先日[せんじつ]:the other day/a few days ago, 動画[どうが]:video|animation|in-betweens (animation)
せ… 先日ですね 動画で その…
I, um... mumble, mumble, mumble...
もにょもにょもにょ
Ms. Satou?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（高橋）佐藤(さとう)先生
（早紀絵）はい！
Yes?
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 土曜日[どようび]:Saturday, 暇[ひま, いとま]:spare time|time (e.g. time it takes to do something)|time off||
今度の土曜日なんですが
お暇ですか？
Are you free this Saturday?
（早紀絵）ああっ！　えっ
（早紀絵）
ええ〜！
Yahoo!
（ひかり）やっほ〜い！
（雪(ゆき)･町(まち)）アハハハッ
No diving in head-first!
頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||, 飛び込む[とびこむ]:to jump in/to leap in|to burst in
（高橋）
頭から飛び込むのは ダメだからな
Ooh, it's cold!
Mr. T! Is my swimsuit cute? Is it?
This feels great! I'm in heaven!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers
（ひかり）
先生！　私の水着
かわいい？　かわいい？
Yep, yep. Very cute, very cute.
（高橋）
はいはい かわいい かわいい
Yay!
暑い[あつい]:hot (weather, etc.)/warm
（ひかり）やった〜！
（高橋）暑くないか？
You aren't too hot?
No, I'm fine.
（町）あっ はい 大丈夫です
If you need anything, just speak up.
何かあったら 言うんだぞ
Okay!
（ひかりたち）は〜い
Thanks for watching them.
お疲れさま[おつかれさま]:thank you/many thanks|that's enough for today
（早紀絵）お疲れさまです
Oh, thank you, too.
お疲れさま[おつかれさま]:thank you/many thanks|that's enough for today
ああ お疲れさまです
Well, I'll leave the rest to you.
よろしく:well/properly|best regards, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
じゃ あと よろしくお願いします
Okay... Huh?
はい　えっ？
You're leaving?
帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
帰られてしまうんですか？
Yeah, this is a good chance for you girls to spend the day together.
せっかく:stone burial chamber, せっかく:with trouble/at great pains|rare, 女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, 過ごす[すごす]:to pass (time)|to overdo (esp. of one's alcohol consumption)|to take care of||, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
ええ せっかくなので
女性 水入らずで過ごしてください
Imori and Kimura will be along later, too.
あとで井森(いもり)と木村(きむら)も来ます
I'll be in the biology prep room.
生物[せいぶつ]:living things/creature|biology, 生物[なまもの]:raw food/perishables, 準備[じゅんび]:preparation/setup/arrangements, 室[しつ]:room|wife (of someone of high rank)|scabbard|, 室[むろ]:greenhouse/icehouse/cellar
私は 生物準備室にいますから
Just bring me the key when you're done.
終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close, 鍵[かぎ, カギ]:key|lock, 鍵[けん]:key (of a piano, etc.), 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
終わったら
鍵だけ持ってきてください
I'll be off, then.
失礼[しつれい, しつらい]:discourtesy|Excuse me|to leave|
では 失礼します
（早紀絵）あっ あの！
（高橋）はい？
W-Wait!
Yes?
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, ゆっくり:slowly/at ease/restful
もう少し ゆっくりされては？
Won't you stay a bit longer?
O-Okay...
は… はあ
Here it comes!
（ひかり）いくよ〜　ほい！
Here you go!
（町）そ〜れ
Got it! Hikari!
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray
（雪）よ〜し ひかり！
Attac—
（ひかり）アタ〜 うっ！
失敗[しっぱい]:failure/mistake/blunder
（雪･町）アハハハッ
（ひかり）うわ〜 失敗した
Aw, I messed up!
（雪）も〜 何やってんの？
Jeez, what was that?
Yukki!
I see... Hikari asked to do this?
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray
（早紀絵）
そうですか　ひかりちゃんが…
Yeah.
（高橋）ええ
But... I mean, the sun is so strong today.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 日ざし[ひざし]:sunlight/rays of the sun
（早紀絵）
でも なんていうか
すごく日ざしが強いですけど
Will she be all right?
大丈夫なんですかね？
それは…
Well...
Yukki! Here it comes!
いくよ:number of nights, いくよ:generations/ages/years
（ひかり）ユッキー いくよ
Okay! Bring it!
（雪）よ〜し こい！
（ひかり）てや〜！
フッ 大丈夫なんでしょう
I think she'll be fine.
I see...
そうですか
Well, why don't you go have some fun, too?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
じゃあ 高橋先生も
楽しむ[たのしむ]:to enjoy (oneself)
楽しんでいかれたら
いいんじゃないですか？
Huh? Oh...
なんという:how (beautiful, etc.)
（高橋）
え？　いや… なんといいますか
Well, I mean...
Rather than having fun myself,
今日は 私よりも
I wanted you to have some fun today.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 楽しむ[たのしむ]:to enjoy (oneself), いただく:to receive/to get|to eat
佐藤先生に
楽しんでいただきたいなと思って
（早紀絵）え？
Huh?
When Hikari asked me about using the pool, I realized
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, プール:(swimming) pool, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
（高橋）
ひかりからプールの話を聞いたとき
ふと思ったんです
that you probably never get to do things like swim in a swimsuit.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers, 泳ぐ[およぐ]:to swim
佐藤先生は 水着で泳ぐとか
そういうことが
できてないんじゃないかって
That's true.
（早紀絵）そうですね
At pools and beaches, people are always around.
海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters, プール:(swimming) pool
海やプールでは
どうしても 人の目があるので
So I'm rather reluctant.
抵抗[ていこう]:resistance|reluctance|resistance||
抵抗がありますね
That's why I thought, if the school pool were reserved for girls only,
校内[こうない]:within a school, プール:(swimming) pool, 女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, 貸し切る[かしきる]:to reserve/to charter
（高橋）
ですので 校内のプールを
女性だけで貸し切れば
you could let go and have fun, for once.
羽を伸ばす[はねをのばす]:to let your hair down/to have fun after a period of work or stress
羽を伸ばせるのではないかと
Bad luck for the boys, though.
男子[だんし]:youth/young man, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
男子には悪いですが
（佐竹(さたけ)）う〜ん
Satake!
落ちる[おちる]:to fall down|to be omitted|to decrease||
（太田(おおた)）佐竹 落ちるなよ
Don't fall!
No need to worry!
心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care, 無用[むよう]:useless|unnecessary|not on business|
（佐竹）心配無用
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 貸し切る[かしきる]:to reserve/to charter, プール:(swimming) pool, 黙る[だまる]:to be silent
女子だけの貸し切りプールと聞いて
黙ってられるか
After hearing the girls reserved the pool, how could I sit around?
おっ うほ〜
なかなか:very/considerably|by no means (with negative verb)
おおっ これは なかなか…
フッ フヘヘ
Now, this is quite a...
C'mon, Ohkawa! Get up here!
おい 太田 お前も来いよ
No, I'm good.
（太田）いや いいわ
（佐竹）ヘヘヘッ そっか〜
Really?
Here comes another one!
まだまだ:still some way to go before the goal/still more to come/much more
（ひかり）まだまだ いくよ〜！
場[ば]:place|field|occasion||, 場[じょう]:place/spot/grounds, 気がせく[きがせく]:to feel under pressure/to feel impatient/to be in a hurry
（高橋）
あとは 私が この場から
いなくなればと気がせいて
That's why I was in such a hurry to leave earlier.
Sorry I made it sound like I was dumping the work on you.
先ほど[さきほど]:some time ago/not long ago/just now, 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 押しつける[おしつける]:to press/to push/to force, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
先ほどは 仕事を
押しつけるみたいになって
すみませんでした
No, not at all!
（早紀絵）そんな…
I appreciate your thoughtfulness.
うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant, 気を遣う[きをつかう]:to pay attention to another's needs/to attend to/to fuss about, いただく:to receive/to get|to eat
うれしいです
気を遣っていただいて
I'm grateful enough that you noticed,
気付く[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise, もらえる:to be able to receive/to be able to take|could you (give me), ありがたい:grateful/thankful/welcome
気付いてもらえただけでも
ありがたいのに
but to arrange all this for me...
場[ば]:place|field|occasion||, 場[じょう]:place/spot/grounds, 設ける[もうける]:to prepare ahead of time|to create/to establish, いただく:to receive/to get|to eat
こういう場まで 設けていただいて
I really...
本当に…
love...
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
好き
My aphrodisiac chance...
チャンス:chance/opportunity
催淫チャンス
Okay, well, I'm heading back now.
帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
じゃあ そういうわけで
私は帰りますので
Have a good time.
楽しむ[たのしむ]:to enjoy (oneself), くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
楽しんでいってください
Uh, no! I don't think your staying will be a problem!
問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||
（早紀絵）
いえ！　ここにいて問題ないかと
But...
（高橋）ですが…
My aphrodisiac effect seems to affect you much less than others!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 比べる[くらべる]:to compare/to make a comparison|to compete, 効果[こうか]:effect/effectiveness|effects (e.g. sound effects, visual effects, special effects), すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 薄い[うすい]:thin|pale|watery||
高橋先生は ほかの人と比べて
催淫効果が すごく薄いようですし
（高橋）えっ いや…
Huh?
Ah, er...
ああ… そうですね
I guess so...
でしょう？
Right?
Maybe I have some sort of resistance to it...
耐性[たいせい]:resistance (e.g. to antibiotics)/tolerance (e.g. drug tolerance), でもある:to also be (formal, literary)/implies that as well as the earlier stated this is also the case|to be ... or something
耐性でもあるんですかね？
I wore a really cute swimsuit.
せっかく:stone burial chamber, せっかく:with trouble/at great pains|rare, 水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers, 着る[きる]:to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down)/to put on|to bear (guilt, etc.)
（早紀絵）
せっかく かわいい水着を
着てきたんですから
くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
見ていってくださいよ
You should stay, so you can see it!
♪ ルンルンルン ルン
Here!
はい！　ほら〜
See?
うわあ:Wow!/Holy smokes!/Aaargh!
（太田）うわあ 佐竹！
Satake!
（早紀絵）あ… エヘヘ
Yes, it is very cute.
とても:very/awfully|(not) at all, かわいらしい:lovely/sweet
ええ　とても かわいらしいですね
Sexy as hell!
エロ〜！
I'm so embarrassed!
恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
（早紀絵）恥ずかし〜！
Mr. Takahashi, would you like to swim, too?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 泳ぐ[およぐ]:to swim
高橋先生も泳ぎませんか？
It'll be great exercise.
運動[うんどう]:exercise|appeal|motion
いい運動になりますよ
Uh, nah... I'm not a good swimmer.
泳ぐ[およぐ]:to swim, 下手[したて, したで]:humble position/inferior|underarm grip on opponent's belt, 下手[しもて]:lower part/foot|left part of the stage (audience's or camera's POV)
ああ いや
私は泳ぐのが下手なんで
Do you mean you can't swim?
ひょっと:possibly/perhaps|unintentionally, カナヅチ:hammer
（早紀絵）
ひょっとして
カナヅチなんですか？
Okay! Ready!
Because "Tetsuo" means "iron man"?
（早紀絵）鉄男(てつお)だけに
（雪）プッ！
Huh?
（高橋）え？
Just kidding...
なんちゃって:just kidding/Not!|ersatz
（早紀絵）なんちゃって〜
アハッ アハハハ
ハア…
What's wrong, Yukki?
（ひかり）どうしたの？　ユッキー
鼻[はな]:nose
（雪）
んん… ちょっと 鼻に水が…
Just... some water up my nose.
Mr. Takahashi,
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional)
（早紀絵）
高橋先生は 生徒から
好きだと告白されたら
what would you do if a student declared their love for you?
どうしますか？
Oh, I saw this drama about that on TV, and...
ドラマ:drama, テレビ:television/TV
そんなドラマを
テレビでやっていてですね
Well, the issue of whether any student is that crazy aside...
酔狂[すいきょう]:whim/vagary/capriciousness, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, 置く[おく]:to put|to leave (behind)|to establish (an organization, a facility, a position, etc.)||
そういう酔狂な生徒が
いるかは置いておくとして
I guess I couldn't return their feelings.
やはり:too/also|still, 相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.), 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 応える[こたえる]:to respond/to answer|to affect
やはり 相手の気持ちに
応えることはできないでしょう
I couldn't think of high schoolers as anything but kids.
高校生[こうこうせい]:senior high school student, 子供[こども]:child/children, 思える[おもえる]:to seem/to appear likely
私にとって 高校生は
どうしても子供としか思えませんし
And above all, they're my students.
教え子[おしえご]:student/disciple
何より 教え子ですからね
I see.
そうですか
私は…
Well, I'm...
I'm neither a child nor your student.
子供[こども]:child/children, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 教え子[おしえご]:student/disciple
私は 子供でも 先生の教え子でも
ないですけどね
フッ
Sure, I know that.
（高橋）ん？　知ってますが
波[なみ]:wave, 波[ぽ]:Poland, 立つ[たつ]:to stand|to find oneself (e.g. in a difficult position)|to depart (on a plane, train, etc.), プール:(swimming) pool
（早紀絵）
ハア… 波が立たないのは
プールだからか
Are waves not forming because this is a pool?
Interviews with Monster Girls
（木村）フウ〜
What're you doing?
遊ぶ[あそぶ, あすぶ]:to play|to mess about (with alcohol, gambling, philandery, etc.)|to be idle||, 遊ぶ[すさぶ]:to grow wild/to rage|to do something one enjoys
（ひかり）
何してんの？　遊ぼ 遊ぼ
C'mon, play with us!
Sorry, we need a break.
休憩[きゅうけい]:rest/break/recess
（井森）ごめん ちょっと休憩
（ひかり）分かった
Okay.
With all that playing, I don't know how they never tire.
ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.), 遊ぶ[あそぶ, あすぶ]:to play|to mess about (with alcohol, gambling, philandery, etc.)|to be idle||, 遊ぶ[すさぶ]:to grow wild/to rage|to do something one enjoys, 疲れる[つかれる]:to get tired|to be worn out (e.g. of well used objects)|to starve
（木村）
しかし ずっと遊んでて
よく疲れないね
Right?
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, へばる:to be exhausted/to be worn out
そうだね
最近すぐ へばっちゃうから
These days, I get tired so easily.
Maybe I'm getting out of shape.
運動[うんどう]:exercise|appeal|motion, 不足[ふそく]:insufficiency/shortage/deficiency
ちょっと運動不足なのかもね
Go for it, Yuki!
雪[ゆき]:snow, 頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place, 任せる[まかせる]:to entrust (e.g. a task) to another|to passively leave to someone else's facilities|to leave to take its natural course||
（町）雪ちゃん 頑張れ〜
（雪）任せて
I got this!
Hey! Having fun?
楽しむ[たのしむ]:to enjoy (oneself)
（高橋）よう 楽しんでるか？
Yes! Aren't you going to swim?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 泳ぐ[およぐ]:to swim
はい　高橋先生は
泳がないんですか？
Nah...
いや…
There!
（早紀絵）それ〜！
Screw it all!
やけくそ:desperate
もう やけくそ〜！
I can't join that...
混ざる[まざる]:to be mixed/to be blended with/to associate with
（高橋）あれには混ざれないよな
（ボールをたたく音）
（ひかり）あっ ごめん
Oops, sorry!
No problem.
いいよ
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
あっ すごいね 京子(きょうこ)
Kyouko, you can talk while you play with us? That's amazing.
遊ぶ[あそぶ, あすぶ]:to play|to mess about (with alcohol, gambling, philandery, etc.)|to be idle||, 遊ぶ[すさぶ]:to grow wild/to rage|to do something one enjoys, ながら:while/during|while, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
遊びながら 話できるんだ
エヘヘ
Yukki!
（ひかり）ユッキー！
（雪）あっ は〜い
Coming!
This is fun. Like watching a craftsman at work.
職人[しょくにん]:worker/mechanic/artisan, 技[わざ, ぎ]:technique/art/skill, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 光景[こうけい]:scene/spectacle/sight
職人の技を見てるようで
楽しいな この光景は
All I'm doing is moving my body.
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 動かす[うごかす]:to move|to inspire|to change||
（町）体を動かしてるだけですよ
The only thing is that when it's far away,
距離[きょり]:distance/range, 離れる[はなれる]:to be separated|to leave|to leave (a job, etc.)|
ただ 距離が離れてくると
it starts to feel like it isn't my body.
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 気になる[きになる]:to be on one's mind|to feel like|to fancy
自分の体じゃないような
気になります
Sort of like playing a video game, I guess.
テレビ:television/TV, ゲーム:game, 感覚[かんかく]:sense/sensation/feeling
テレビゲームをやっているような
感覚ですかね
Swimsuit
Item
I get it.
Swimsuit
Item
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed
（高橋）なるほどな
Swimsuit
Item
If there were a game tournament like that, you'd definitely place first.
ゲーム:game, 大会[たいかい]:convention/tournament/mass meeting
そういうゲーム大会が
あったら
町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||, 等[など]:et cetera|or something|the likes of, 等[とう]:class|et cetera|equal, 賞[しょう]:prize/award
町が１等賞かな
You think so?
どうですかね？
There are only two other dullahans in the world.
世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||
世界には
デュラハンの方が
あと２人
いるそうですから
Even if you placed last, you'd still get bronze.
仮[け]:lacking substance and existing in name only/something without substance, 仮[かり]:temporary|fictitious|hypothetical, 銅[かね, かな]:money|metal, 銅[どう, あかがね]:copper (Cu)|bronze (medal), メダル:medal
仮にビリでも
銅メダルじゃないか
That's true!
そうですね
Don't you think that
伝承[でんしょう]:handing down (information)/legend/tradition
（町）デュラハンの伝承って
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance
ほかのデミのとは
少し違うと思いませんか？
legends of dullahans are a little different than those of other demis?
Like, how were dullahans associated with an image of a knight on horseback?
デュラハンは なぜ
馬に乗る[うまにのる]:to get on a horse/to mount a horse, 戦う[たたかう]:to make war (on)|to compete (against)|to struggle (against adversities, etc.), 騎士[きし]:knight, イメージ:(one's) image
馬に乗って戦う騎士という
イメージができたのかなって
That's true. Not many other demis
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 伝承[でんしょう]:handing down (information)/legend/tradition
確かに ほかのデミの伝承では
have legends that specify classes or jobs, like a knight.
騎士[きし]:knight, 具体的[ぐたいてき]:concrete/tangible/definite, 身分[みぶん]:social position/social status, 職[しょく, そく]:job|duties|trade, 職[しき]:agency (government department between a ministry and a bureau under the ritsuryo system), 得る[うる]:to be able to .../can ...|to get, 得る[える]:to get|to understand|to receive something undesirable (e.g. a punishment)|, 少ない[すくない]:few/a little/scarce
騎士のような具体的な身分や
職を得ているものは 少ないな
I tried giving it some thought.
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
（町）
それで ちょっと考えてみたんです
Maybe long ago, a great dullahan was an accomplished knight,
過去[かこ]:the past|a past (i.e. a personal history one would prefer remained secret)|past (tense)|, 騎士[きし]:knight, 大[おお]:big/large, 大[だい]:the large part of|big|approximate size||, 活躍[かつやく]:activity (esp. energetic)/great efforts|to flourish, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
過去に騎士として大活躍した
すごいデュラハンがいて
and his image was the one that stayed most vivid through history.
イメージ:(one's) image, 色[いろ]:colour|complexion|appearance||, 色[しょく]:counter for colours, 濃い[こい]:deep (colour)|strong (flavour, smell, etc.)|thick (consistency)||, 残る[のこる]:to remain/to be left
そのイメージが
色濃く残ってるのかなって
I see...
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed
（高橋）
なるほどな
If there were a dullahan knight of such strength and vitality,
騎士[きし]:knight
そんな抜山蓋世(ばつざんがいせい)な
デュラハンの騎士がいたら
I'm sure he'd be a legend.
伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore
伝説だろうな
And if it started with him, the image's specificity makes sense.
元[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 元[げん]:unknown (e.g. in an equation)|element (of a set)|yuan (monetary unit of China)|, 個人[こじん]:individual/private person/personal, イメージ:(one's) image, 具体性[ぐたいせい]:concreteness/feasibility, 高い[たかい]:high/tall|expensive
元が個人なら
イメージの具体性が高いのも
うなずける:to nod/to bow one's head in assent/to agree
うなずけるし
When you think of it that way, the other legends fit, as well.
伝承[でんしょう]:handing down (information)/legend/tradition, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||, つじつまが合う[つじつまがあう]:to be consistent/to be coherent
（町）
ほかの伝承も そう考えると
つじつまが合って
Dullahans are known as harbingers of death,
死[し]:death|death penalty (by strangulation or decapitation)|(an) out, 予言[よげん]:prediction/prophecy/prognostication, 予言[かねごと]:promise/prediction, 存在[そんざい]:existence/being
デュラハンは死を予言する存在だと
言われていますが
which means a dullahan is the last thing you see.
要[かなめ]:pivot|vital point|Japanese photinia, 要[よう]:cornerstone|requirement|necessary, 出会う[であう]:to meet (by chance)|to meet (e.g. of rivers, highways, etc.)|to emerge and engage (an enemy), 最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments
要は 出会ったが最後ということで
Maybe the idea that they throw a basin of blood on those who stand at their door
戸口[とぐち]:door/doorway, 戸口[ここう]:houses and inhabitants/population, 立つ[たつ]:to stand|to find oneself (e.g. in a difficult position)|to depart (on a plane, train, etc.)
戸口に立つ人に
いっぱい:one defeat, いっぱい:amount necessary to fill a container (e.g. cupful, spoonful, etc.)/drink (usu. alcoholic)|full, 血[ち]:blood/consanguinity, 浴びせる[あびせる]:to pour on, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
タライいっぱいの血を
浴びせるなんていうのも
was what the deaths of people killed by dullahans looked like.
手に掛かる[てにかかる]:to fall into someone's hands/to place oneself in someone's power, 最期[さいご]:one's last moment/one's death/one's end
デュラハンの手に掛かった人の
最期が
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
そう見えたんじゃないかって…
I've also heard that those
両[りょう]:both (e.g. both shoulders, etc.)|ryo (obsolete unit of currency)|41-42 g (one sixteenth of a kin)||, 両[もろ, モロ]:both|many|together, 潰す[つぶす]:to smash|to shut down|to thwart||
ほかにも デュラハンを見た人は
両の目をムチで潰される などなど
who see a dullahan have their eyes lashed out, and so on.
Now that I think about it, all the legends are like that.
よくよく:the one after next, よくよく:exceedingly/very, 挙げる[あげる]:to raise|to do up (one's hair)|to fly (a kite, etc.)||, ばかり:only/merely|approximately
（高橋）
よくよく挙げると
そういうのばかりだな
Got it!
オーライ:all right/OK
オーライ　それ！
There!
But aren't there are also other stories?
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
（高橋）
もっと違う話のも あるだろ？
Like that dullahans can't cross a flowing stream.
流れる[ながれる]:to stream|to be washed away|to drift||, 川[かわ, がわ]:river/stream|the .... river, 渡る[わたる]:to cross over/to go across|to extend, ことができる:can (do)/to be able to (do)/can be done
デュラハンは 流れる川の上を
渡ることができないとか
What do you think that one means?
どういう:somehow/how/in what way, 理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
これには
どういう理由があると思う？
That must be
プールサイド:poolside, 理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
それは 今 私が
プールサイドにいる理由と同じで…
for the same reason I'm staying here, beside the pool.
Yeah, that's true.
そうだな
It's scary to think what would happen if you dropped your head in the water.
頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||, 落とす[おとす]:to drop|to clean off (dirt, makeup, paint, etc.)|to lose (a match)||, ゾッと:shuddering/shivering/trembling
水の中に頭を落としたらと思うと
ゾッとするな
In a pool, it would only be a bit dangerous,
プール:(swimming) pool, 危ない[あぶない]:dangerous|in danger|uncertain||, 済む[すむ]:to finish|to merely result in something less severe than expected|to feel at ease|
（町）
プールだったら まだ
危ないで済みますが
but if it happened in a running stream...
流れ[ながれ]:stream/current|course of events, 川[かわ, がわ]:river/stream|the .... river, 場合[ばあい]:case/situation
流れのある川で そうなった場合…
ハック:hack
（デュラハン）
ハックシュン！　あっ…
It'd be over. No way out.
終わり[おわり]:the end, しよう:way/method|(technical) specification, しよう:use/application/employment
終わりです
どうしようもありません
I guess that means
川[かわ, がわ]:river/stream|the .... river, 渡る[わたる]:to cross over/to go across|to extend
さしものデュラハンも
川を渡ってまで
even dullahans wouldn't chance pursuing anyone into a river.
相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.), 追う[おう]:to chase|to follow (a set order, a trend, etc.)|to drive out||, リスク:risk, リスク:reduced instruction set computer/RISC, 冒す[おかす]:to brave|to harm|to desecrate|
相手を追うリスクは
冒さなかったということか
I like that legend. It's one I can relate to.
伝承[でんしょう]:handing down (information)/legend/tradition, 親近感[しんきんかん]:affinity, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
この伝承は
親近感を覚えて好きです
Macchi...
（ひかり）マッチー
（高橋･町）ん？
You're so busy talking, your body's stopped moving.
おしゃべり:chattering/talk|chatty, 夢中[むちゅう]:daze/(in a) trance/ecstasy, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 動く[うごく]:to move|to operate|to be touched||
おしゃべりに夢中で
体が動いてないぞ〜
Oops... Sorry.
アハハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
（町）アハハ　ごめんね
So anyway, so anyway! Listening to you guys made me think...
そいでさ そいでさ
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., ちらちら:falling lightly (e.g. snow, petals, confetti)/fluttering|flickering
話 ちらちら聞いてて
思ったんだけど
You've never gone underwater, have you?
潜る[くぐる]:to go under|to dive (into or under the water)|to evade|, 潜る[もぐる, むぐる]:to dive (into or under water)|to get under|to hide oneself (esp. from the government)
マッチーって 水の中に
潜ったことないんじゃない？
Gone underwater... You mean my head?
潜る[くぐる]:to go under|to dive (into or under the water)|to evade|, 潜る[もぐる, むぐる]:to dive (into or under water)|to get under|to hide oneself (esp. from the government), 頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||
潜るって 頭のほうがってこと？
Yeah.
そうそう:so long/so often|oh, yes!, そうそう:funeral/burial rites|attendance at a funeral
そうそう
You're right, I haven't.
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken
確かに ないな
Aw, what a waste!
もったい:superior airs/air of importance|overemphasis
ええ〜？　もったいないな〜
Everything looks really pretty underwater.
景色[けしき, けいしょく]:scenery/scene/landscape, きれい:pretty/lovely|clean
水の中の景色って
すご〜く きれいなのにな
I can't believe you've never seen it!
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
見たことないなんてな〜
What a terrible waste!
もったい:superior airs/air of importance|overemphasis
もったいないな〜　ヘヘッ
ああ…
ドキドキ:thump-thump/bang-bang/pit-a-pat, してき:historic/historical, してき:pointing out/identification
（町）
わ〜 ちょっと ドキドキしてきた
I'm starting to feel a little nervous...
Who is Mr. Takahashi talking to?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
（雪）
先生は
誰と電話してるの？
Macchi's dad.
（ひかり）
マッチーのパパ
許可[きょか]:permission/approval|to permit, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
水ん中 入るのに
許可もらってるんだって
Mr. T wanted to ask permission for her to go in the water.
Is it really necessary, just for a few seconds under?
潜る[くぐる]:to go under|to dive (into or under the water)|to evade|, 潜る[もぐる, むぐる]:to dive (into or under water)|to get under|to hide oneself (esp. from the government), 必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity
（町）
ちょっと潜るだけなのに
必要なのかな？
It's very important.
大切[たいせつ, たいせち]:important|beloved|careful, 大切[おおぎり]:large cut (e.g. of meat)|last piece of the day's programme/last act of a play
（早紀絵）大切なことよ
Even if you know you'll get permission,
許可[きょか]:permission/approval|to permit, もらえる:to be able to receive/to be able to take|could you (give me)
許可がもらえると
分かっていても
contacting him to ask is very important.
きちんと:properly/accurately|neatly, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|, とても:very/awfully|(not) at all, 大切[たいせつ, たいせち]:important|beloved|careful, 大切[おおぎり]:large cut (e.g. of meat)|last piece of the day's programme/last act of a play
きちんと連絡するのは とても大切
Ms. Satou, what are you doing with only your head above water?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||
（雪）
先生 頭だけ出して
何やってるんですか？
やっぱり:too/also|still, 水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers, 恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful, ブクブク:bulging/swelling (e.g. with water)/loose-fitting or baggy (clothing)
やっぱり 水着を見られるのは
恥ずかし… ブクブク
I'm still embarrassed to be seen in my swimsuit...
That's done!
（高橋）お待たせ
（町たち）ん？
We're ready to go!
準備[じゅんび]:preparation/setup/arrangements, オーケー:OK
（高橋）準備オーケーだ
I'll hold your head, Machi.
町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||, 頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
町の頭は 俺が持つな
Okay.
オーケー:OK
（ひかり）オーケー
Everyone ready?
（高橋）みんな いいか？
Yeah!
（ひかり･雪）は〜い！
Okay, here we go.
（高橋）じゃあ いくぞ
（息を吸う音）
One, two...
（高橋）せ〜の！
（町）ん…
あ…
ああ…
わあ…
（町）プハッ
How was that? Could you see?
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
（高橋）
どうだ？　ちゃんと見えたか？
It was so pretty!
（高橋）ハハッ　そうか
Yeah? I didn't really get that, but good for you.
よく分からんが よかった よかった
Macchi, go under with me next!
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 潜る[くぐる]:to go under|to dive (into or under the water)|to evade|, 潜る[もぐる, むぐる]:to dive (into or under water)|to get under|to hide oneself (esp. from the government)
マッチー 今度は私と潜ろう
Then me!
次[つぎ]:next/following|stage, 次[じ]:next|hypo- (i.e. containing an element with low valence)|order
（雪）その次 私ね
（町）うん
Sure!
Hey, take it easy. Too much too soon is dangerous.
You guys, come underwater with us.
潜る[くぐる]:to go under|to dive (into or under the water)|to evade|, 潜る[もぐる, むぐる]:to dive (into or under water)|to get under|to hide oneself (esp. from the government), とっても:very/awfully|(not) at all, きれい:pretty/lovely|clean
（雪）
ねえねえ ２人も潜ろうよ
とってもきれいだよ
It's really pretty.
Uh... No...
（井森）え〜 いや…
Okay, let's do it!
潜る[くぐる]:to go under|to dive (into or under the water)|to evade|, 潜る[もぐる, むぐる]:to dive (into or under water)|to get under|to hide oneself (esp. from the government)
（木村）よし 潜るか！
Yuki, get her other side.
Sh-Shizuka?
雪[ゆき]:snow, 反対[はんたい]:opposition/resistance|reverse, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
（井森）ちょっ 静香(しずか)
（木村）雪 反対 持って
Okay!
Here we go! One, two...
Wha... Yuki? No... Wait, wait!
You can't get away now!
（木村）いくぞ〜
せ〜の！
Go!
（木村･雪）それ！
（井森）うわ〜！
楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
（町）
楽しかった〜
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 驚く[おどろく]:to be surprised/to be astonished, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
（木村）
あんな驚いた顔 初めて見たわ
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently
今度また行こうな
（扉が開く音）
（高橋）なんだ まだいたのか
Oh, you're still here?
焼ける[やける]:to burn/to be roasted|to be jealous
ん？　焼けたな
You got sunburned.
えっ！
エヘヘ
Will you be okay?
（高橋）大丈夫なのか？
I'll be fine. After a day's rest, it'll be better.
ゆっくり:slowly/at ease/restful, 治る[なおる]:to be cured/to get well|to get mended, 平気[へいき]:coolness/calmness|all right
（ひかり）
１日ゆっくりしてれば
治るから平気
Is that why you suggested a Saturday?
土曜[どよう]:Saturday
（高橋）
だから 土曜って言ったのか
You were worried about me?
心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
（ひかり）心配してくれたんだ？
Sure.
そりゃ:very/extremely|that is
（高橋）そりゃ
Mr. T, thanks.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, ありがと:Thank you
（ひかり）先生 ありがとね
（高橋）ん？
Since I planned this,
企画[きかく]:planning/project/plan
（ひかり）私が企画したから
you prioritized my wanting to have fun, right?
遊ぶ[あそぶ, あすぶ]:to play|to mess about (with alcohol, gambling, philandery, etc.)|to be idle||, 遊ぶ[すさぶ]:to grow wild/to rage|to do something one enjoys, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 優先[ゆうせん]:preference/priority/precedence
私が遊びたいって気持ちを
優先させてくれたんでしょ？
The idea of a vampire getting in a pool, under the summer sun...
バンパイア:vampire, 夏[なつ]:summer, 夏[か]:Xia (dynasty of China; perhaps mythological), 日ざし[ひざし]:sunlight/rays of the sun, プール:(swimming) pool, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
バンパイアが 夏の日ざしの下で
プールなんて
If Himari hadn't asked me to,
頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|
ひまりちゃんに頼まれなかったら
I might have been too scared to let you.
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid, 承諾[しょうだく]:consent/acquiescence/agreement
怖くて 承諾できたかどうか
分からん
屋内[おくない]:indoor (court, pool, etc.), プール:(swimming) pool, 察する[さっする]:to guess/to sense|to sympathize with
だって 屋内プールだと
みんなが察しちゃって
Well, if I'd asked for an indoor pool, everyone would've seen through me.
And the next time we played, they would have gone out of their way, right?
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 遊びに行く[あそびにいく]:to go on a trip/to go out to play/to go and visit (a friend), 遠慮[えんりょ]:reserve|declining|forethought
今度 遊びに行くとき
私に遠慮しちゃいそうでしょ？
I wouldn't want that.
嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
そういうの 嫌だし
No.
ああ
Well, bye!
（ひかり）じゃあね〜
Yep. See you on Monday.
月曜[げつよう]:Monday
（高橋）ああ また月曜な
Shibasaki Prefectural High School
（ひかり）
♪ フン フフフン
♪ フンフ〜ン フフ〜ン
フンフン:uh-huh
フンフン… あっ
うう…
Good morning, Mr. T!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, おはよう:good morning
先生 おはよう
Shibasaki Prefectural High School
Yep, morning.
おはよう:good morning
ああ おはよう
ニッヒヒ
Hey, Mr. T...
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
ねえ 先生
This is the spot where we first met, isn't it?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 最初[さいしょ]:beginning/outset/first, 所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places
私と先生が最初に会った所って
ここだったよね
Back then, the cherry blossoms were in full bloom.
桜[さくら, サクラ]:cherry tree|decoy|hired applauder|, 満開[まんかい]:full bloom
あのときは 桜が満開だったな
Hey, Mr. T, remember what you said the other day?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
先生さ この前 言ってたよね
That vampires must feel constricted by living in modern society.
バンパイア:vampire, 現代[げんだい]:nowadays/modern era/modern times, 社会[しゃかい]:society/public|social studies, 窮屈[きゅうくつ]:narrow|formal|constrained|
バンパイアは
現代社会で窮屈してるって
But you know what I think?
でも 私は思うの
Having people who cry with you when you're sad,
悲しい[かなしい]:sad/sorrowful, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 泣く[なく]:to cry/to weep/to sob
悲しいときに 一緒に泣いたり
and laugh with you when you're having fun...
楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|
楽しいときに 一緒に笑ったり
窮屈[きゅうくつ]:narrow|formal|constrained|
ちょっと窮屈でも
Even if it's a little constricting,
spending time with those people is much more precious
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 過ごす[すごす]:to pass (time)|to overdo (esp. of one's alcohol consumption)|to take care of||
みんなで 同じ時間を過ごすほうが
ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.), 大切[たいせつ, たいせち]:important|beloved|careful, 大切[おおぎり]:large cut (e.g. of meat)|last piece of the day's programme/last act of a play, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
ずっと大切で ずっと楽しいって
and much more fun.
So I think vampires today are happier!
だからね
バンパイア:vampire, 幸せ[しあわせ, しやわせ]:happiness/good fortune/luck
今のバンパイアのほうが幸せ
I see.
そうか
Well, I'll be heading in!
（ひかり）それでは これにて
Hey, wait a sec.
ちょい:heirship, ちょい:just a minute/short time|somewhat
（高橋）ああ ちょい待ち
（ひかり）何？
What's up?
Write your name before you go in.
書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
（高橋）
これに名前 書いてから行ってね
List of Tardy Students
Hey, Mr. T, do you remember?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|
ねえ 先生 覚えてる？
Yeah, enough of that. Write.
書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
もう そういうのいいから 書いて〜
Come on, please! Listen to me!
お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
（ひかり）ねえ お願い　聞いて！
おう 何だ？
Okay, what?
Himari wouldn't do my hair, saying I should do it myself!
かげん:(moon's) last quarter, かげん:lower limit|infimum
（ひかり）
ひまりが いいかげん
１人でやれって
髪[かみ]:hair (on the head), 結う[ゆう, いう]:to do up (hair)/to braid/to fasten, 先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.), 学校[がっこう]:school
髪 結ってくれなくて
先に学校行っちゃって
She left without me. And then, and then, I was late, doing my hair!
遅れる[おくれる]:to be late/to be delayed/to fall behind schedule
それで それで
１人でやってたら遅れちゃって
Ah, I see. Now write.
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed, 書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
なるほどな〜　書いて
（ひかり）え〜？
Aw...
Please, Mr. Magistrate!
代官[だいかん]:Edo-period prefectural governor (magistrate, bailiff), 様[ざま]:mess|-ways|in the act of ...|, 様[さま]:Mr.|makes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)|state
お代官様〜
At first, it was purely out of interest.
最初[さいしょ]:beginning/outset/first, 純粋[じゅんすい]:pure/true/genuine, 興味[きょうみ]:interest (in something)/curiosity (about something)/zest (for)
（高橋）
最初は 純粋は興味だけだった
Hmph. I thought it would work.
チェッ
I started to have contact with these girls.
接する[せっする]:to touch|to receive (e.g. visitor)|to receive (news)||
（高橋）
この子たちと接するようになって
And I began to feel a desire to help them.
助け[たすけ]:assistance/help/aid
助けになってやりたいと
思うようになって
But many times, I learned even more from them,
むしろ:rather/better/instead, むしろ:woven mat (esp. one made of straw)|seat, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
だけど むしろ こっちが
教えられることのほうが多くて
and I got even more help from them.
逆[ぎゃく]:reverse|converse (of a hypothesis, etc.)|inverse (function), 逆[さか]:inverse/reverse, 助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|, 少ない[すくない]:few/a little/scarce
逆に 助けられたことだって
少なくはなかった
I haven't spoken with them nearly enough.
まだまだ:still some way to go before the goal/still more to come/much more, 語る[かたる]:to talk about|to recite|to indicate, 足りる[たりる]:to be sufficient|to be worth doing|to be sufficient
まだまだ 語り足りない
Even my dad said I shouldn't rely on Himari all the time!
甘える[あまえる]:to behave like a spoiled child/to fawn on|to take advantage of, ばかり:only/merely|approximately
パパも ひまりに甘えてばかりじゃ
ダメだって言うし
冷たい[つめたい, つべたい]:cold (to the touch)/chilly|coldhearted
みんな冷たいの〜
Everyone's so mean!
It's the third time, so you get to stay after school and clean up.
回[かい]:counter for occurrences|a time|inning (baseball)||, 放課後[ほうかご]:after school, 居残る[いのこる]:to stay behind/to remain/to work overtime, 掃除[そうじ]:cleaning/sweeping/dusting
今日で３回目だから
放課後 居残り掃除な
（ひかり）
え〜っ？　そこをなんとか！
Please! Anything but that!
Well, I have a faculty meeting to get to.
職員[しょくいん]:staff member/personnel, 会議[かいぎ]:meeting/conference/session
（高橋）
さ〜て 職員会議 職員会議
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（ひかり）先生！
Mr. T!
I need many, many more interviews
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 語る[かたる]:to talk about|to recite|to indicate
（高橋）
俺は もっともっと語りたい
with these demis!
Interviews with Monster Girls
語る[かたる]:to talk about|to recite|to indicate
デミちゃんと語りたい
The events of a mysterious world,
♪〜
Like the ones you hear of in fairy tales,
Are actually closer than you think
Just like the way you and I met!
When I stood up tall to gaze at
The familiar scenery outside my window,
Even days that felt like torture seemed precious somehow.
Stuck in my heart, I can't put them into words
How should I try to put these feelings into words?
Laughing over stupid things...
Getting mad over small details...
We'll keep carving these trivial moments into our hearts.
Sometimes I'm feeling sad...
But when I'm with you, I'm so happy!
We'll keep on building these irreplaceable moments,
〜♪
And little by little, we'll come to understand one another.